Marcus Taylor

Brooklyn, New York • (757) 880-4645 • taylor.marcus99@gmail.com

https://www.marcustaylor.org/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/taylor-marcus/

SUMMARY

Senior Consulting professional with a focus on data, Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML), and sustainability. Over 5 years of data science, data analytics, and AI / ML experience and an extensive record of applying those experiences successfully to clients at the federal, state, and local levels.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Deloitte, Senior Consultant - AI & Engineering, Arlington, VA

Jul 2021 - Present

Acted as an Analyst, Consultant, and Senior Consultant for the largest global professional services network across several federal, state, and local clients in **data modernization**, **AI/ML**, **GIS**, and **economic development** initiatives.

- Acted as full-stack developer on data analytics platform for federal client to integrate AI into and modernize 100,000+ exchange standards across 9,000+ systems to drive digital interoperability using R, Python, Java, and AngularJS.
- Built proof-of-concept of geospatial analytics tool for a state Department of Fish & Wildlife which used Google Earth Engine, Esri, and Python to monitor ecological condition across the state, progress toward strategic objectives, and secure stakeholder support for data-driven environmental policy decisions in the state.
- Developed 3 VBA-enabled workstreams to optimize staffing and resource allocation for state Department of Fish & Wildlife which reduced resource gaps by 49% while expanding mission coverage by 36%. Hosted 10+ training sessions for 300+ SMEs to effectively educate clients on developed workflows.
- Created proof-of-concept platform to modernize state Water Resources Control Board's lead and copper service line inventory testing and compliance workflows using Salesforce and ArcGIS online. Coordinated Agile sprint planning, user story generation between Developer and UX teams using Jira.

Virginia Tech, Undergraduate Teaching Assistant, Blacksburg, VA

Aug 2020 - May 2021

Served as a Teaching Assistant for a Systems Analysis class by assisting to **restructure the class from in-person to virtual during the onset of the Covid-19 pandemic** and acting as a **liaison and mentor** for over 100 students per semester.

- Completed 4-day training in communication skills, teaching and learning strategies, and interactive online technologies.
- Assigned grades, provided feedback on projects, and hosted regular online office hours to interface with students.

Custom Vinyl Products LLC, Production Team Intern, Williamsburg, VA

Jun 2019 - Aug 2020

Interned on production floor of local vinyl window and door manufacturing business to **identify inefficiencies**, **opportunities for improvement**, and **provide recommendations** for updates to standard operating procedures.

- Conducted time and motion studies on different production stations to identify inefficiencies in process.
- Managed small team of 3-4 employees to cut, weld, and assemble vinyl products.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Active US Secret Security Clearance
- Google certified Generative AI Leader

EDUCATION

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Virginia Tech), Blacksburg, VA

Sept 2017 - May 2021

BS in FinTech and Big Data Analytics

• Summa Cum Laude

BS in Business Information Technology (concentration in Computer Decision Support Systems)

• Summa Cum Laude

SKILLS

- R/RStudio
- HTML / CSS / Tailwind
- Microsoft Office 365

- Python
- VBA / Visual Basic
- SQL

- JavaScript / React
- AI / ML engineering
- Database engineering